visme.co 2019-08-01

# Visme Privacy Policy | Visme

Last Updated on April 4th, 2019

**Introduction.**

1.1 Visme (“Company,” or “we,” or “us,” or “our”) is committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website and service users (“users,” or “you”). VISME provides ­­­­­­­­­­­­­presentation tools (“Service” or “Company Service”) via the Company website(s) offered from time to time at the URL www.visme.co (collectively, the “Site,” or “Sites”). The Company Service is owned and operated by EASY WEBCONTENT, Inc (“Company”, “we” or “us”).

1.2 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to your personal data, in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

(a) Some of our policies are different when our Site is used for K-12 school purposes and these policies are displayed at the end of each Section where such policies may differ from our standard policy.

This document tells you how we use your data and what your rights are with respect to that data.

1.3 Terms of Service. Use of the Company Service is subject to the terms of our Terms of Service through our online form, which is hereby incorporated and made part of this Privacy Policy. By using the Company Service, you agree to be bound by our Terms of Service.

1.4 Your use of the Company Service is subject to the terms and conditions set forth in this Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”).

1.5 We continually strive to find new ways to enhance your experience with the Company Service and we may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our privacy practices. You are encouraged to review this Privacy Policy periodically and to check the “Last Updated” date at the top of the Privacy Policy for the most recent version. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of notice through the Website, the Application, or any other part of the Company Service.

We can update this Policy anytime we want.

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY. BY ACCESSING OR USING THE COMPANY SERVICE, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND, AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY ALL THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OUR TERMS OF SERVICE. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO SUCH TERMS, EXIT THIS PAGE AND DO NOT ACCESS OR USE THE COMPANY SERVICE.

**2\. How we use your personal data.**

2.1 In this Section 2 we have set out:

  * (a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;
  * (b) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
  * (c) the legal bases of the processing.

2.2 Types and Uses of Collected Information. Company collects two types of information about you, “Personally Identifiable Information” and “Non-Personally Identifiable Information.”

**Personally Identifiable Information, General Users**

2.3 Personally identifiable information is information that identifies a specific person. When you engage in certain activities via the Company Service, including but not limited to creating an account, sending feedback, or otherwise participating in the Company Service (collectively, “Identification Activities”), we may ask you to provide certain information about yourself.  If you elect to engage in an Identification Activity, we may ask you to provide us with certain personal information about yourself, such as your name, address, email address, telephone number and/or any other information you provide to us, to create your account of profile, send communications about them to you, and populate forms for future transactions. 

_Each of the following sections tells you what kind of data we collect, why we collect it and the legal reason we have the right to do so._.

2.3 We may process your account data (“account data”). The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.4 We may process data about your use of our website and services (“usage data”). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use]. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analyzing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.5 We may process your account data (“account data”). The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.6 We may process your information included in your personal profile on our website (“profile data”). The profile data may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, profile pictures, gender, interests and hobbies, educational details and employment details. The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.7 We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our services (“publication data”). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.8 We may process information contained in any inquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services (“inquiry data”). The inquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.9 We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website (“transaction data”). The transaction data may include first and last names, an email address to be used as a login, billing contact information, credit card number and a password. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests.

2.10 We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (“notification data”). The notification data may be processed [for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.11 We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“correspondence data”). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.12 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

2.13 In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

2.14 Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us unless we prompt you to do so.

**Personally Identifiable Information, K-12**

**2.3 for K-12** Personally Identifiable Information, also referred to herein as “Covered Information,” is information gathered by us that is descriptive of a student or otherwise identifies a student, including, but not limited to, student’s email, first and last name,  IP address, telephone number, other information that allows online contact. Covered Information shall include any personally identifiable information or materials:

(a)  in any media or format, including but not limited to our online Service;

(i) “Online Service” includes cloud computing services.

(b) is created or provided by a student, or the student’s parent or legal guardian, to us in the course of the student’s, parent’s, or legal guardian’s use of the Site or Service or K­12 school purposes;

(i) “K-12 school purposes” means purposes that customarily take place at the direction of the K­12 school, teacher, or school district or aid in the administration of school activities, including, but not limited to, instruction in the classroom or at home, administrative activities, and collaboration between students, school personnel, or parents, or are for the use and benefit of the school.

(c) is created or provided by an employee or agent of the K­12 school, school district, local education agency, or county office of education, to us.

(d) we may use Covered Information to product Services to you solely for K-12 school purposes. 

(e) we will not use any Covered Information to deliver targeted advertising.

(f) we will not use any Covered Information to amass a profile about a K-12 student.

Original Sections 2.3 (a)(b)(c)(d)(e)(f)(g)(h)(i)(j) and (k) are deleted.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

2.15 Non-Personally Identifiable Information is information that does not identify a specific person. This type of information may include things like the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) of the website you visited before coming to the Company Service or otherwise participating in the Company Service, the URL of the website you visit after leaving the Company Service, the type of browser you are using, your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, mobile carrier information, mobile device information, or general and/or aggregated location data that does constitute Personally Identifiable Information. We, and/or our authorized Third-Party Service Providers, may automatically collect this information when you visit or use the Company Service using electronic tools like Cookies and Web beacons or Pixel tags, as described below in this Privacy Policy.  We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to troubleshoot, administer the Company Service, analyze trends, gather demographic information, comply with applicable law, and cooperate with law enforcement activities. We may also share this information with our authorized Third-Party Service Providers to measure the overall effectiveness of our products and services.

**2.15 for K-12** Non-Personally Identifiable Information is information that does not identify a specific person. This type of information may include things like the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) of the website you visited before coming to the Company Service or otherwise participating in the Company Service, the URL of the website you visit after leaving the Company Service, the type of browser you are using,  or general and/or aggregated location data that does constitute Personally Identifiable Information. We, and/or our authorized Third-Party Service Providers, may automatically collect this information when you visit or use the Company Service using electronic tools like Cookies and Web beacons or Pixel tags, as described below in this Privacy Policy. We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to improve our Service, to improving educational products and to demonstrate the effectiveness of our products or Services, including in our marketing materials.  

**3\. Providing your personal data to others**

Here’s where we tell you whether we are going to share your data with others.

3.1 We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies, this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy.

**3.1 for K-12**.  We will not sell, lease, rent, trade or otherwise make available a student’s information, including covered information, except that in the event of a purchase, merger or other type of acquisition of us by another party, that party may use Covered Information in the same manner we do.   Sections 3.2 – 3.7 do not apply to K-12.

3.2 Financial transactions relating to our website and services may be handled by our payment services providers. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.

3.3 We may disclose your inquiry data to one or more of those selected third-party suppliers of services via APIs identified on our website for the purpose of enabling them to connect your account with their Services. Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the inquiry data that we supply to it. Each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party’s use of your personal data.

If you use our Service or Site to connect with other parties, you should check their Privacy Policy; we’re not responsible for those.

3.4 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 3, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

**4\. About cookies**

4.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies, cookies and more cookies. Why cookies? Because they leave crumbs. We can use these to track your web behavior; both on our site and sometimes where you have from and where you go after our site. We may use these crumbs to track you. Not for anything nefarious, just so we can improve how we deliver our Service.

4.2 Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

4.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

**5\. Cookies that we use**

5.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * (a) authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and services, and as you navigate our website.
  * (b) status – we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website.
  * (c) personalization – we use cookies [to store information about your preferences and to personalize the website and services for you.
  * (d) security – we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally.
  * (e) advertising – we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you. This section (e) does not apply to K-12.
  * (f) analysis – we use cookies [to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services; and
  * (g) cookie consent – we use cookies [to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally.

**6\. Cookies used by our service providers**

6.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

6.2 We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.

**7\. Managing cookies**

7.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

  * (a) https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
  * (b) https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);
  * (c) http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);
  * (d) https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
  * (e) https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
  * (f) https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).

If you want to shut off cookies and prevent Sites from tracking you, here’s how.

7.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

7.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

**8\. Analytics**

We continuously improve our websites and our products, and we utilize different third-party web analytics tools to help us do so. We are interested in how visitors use our websites, our desktop tools, our mobile applications, what they like and dislike, and where they have problems. Our products, desktop tools and mobile applications, as available from time to time, use analytical tools to understand feature usage patterns, to enhance and improve your product experience and offer you specific usage tips and guidance. In connection with normal business operations, as well as to increase functionality and enhance your user experience, this usage information may be linked to personal information that we have about individual users. We maintain ownership of this data and we do not share this type of data about individual users with third parties.

**8.1 for K-12**.  This usage information will not be linked to Covered Information that we have about individual users.

This information is used solely to assist us in maintaining a more effective and useful websites and products for our customers. This data will not be shared with third parties without your prior consent or unless required by law.

**9\. SECURITY OF INFORMATION**.

9.1 You may be able to access your Personally Identifiable Information via the Company Service with your password and username. This password is encrypted. We advise against sharing your password with anyone.  If you access your account via a third-party site or service, you may have additional or different sign-in protections via that third-party site or service. You need to prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-in mechanism appropriately and limiting access to your computer, browser, or mobile device by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. If we believe that the security of your information may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. 

9.2 We are committed to taking all reasonable precautions to safeguard the privacy of personal information which has been provided by its users. We use technical, contractual, administrative and physical security steps to protect your personal information. Security measures such as restricted access and the use of passwords and encryption have been adopted to protect your personal information against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. Our employees have been trained to respect your privacy at all times and those employees with access to your personal information shall use your personal information strictly in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

9.3 Please be aware that no data transmission over the Internet or via e-mail is completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee protection of all personal information in all cases. For example, we cannot guarantee protection against interception, misappropriation, misuse, or alteration, or that your information will not be disclosed or accessed by the unauthorized acts of others. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Materials posted to online forums such as bulletin boards or chat rooms are public, not secure, and may be viewed by anyone. Any personal information you post may be collected and used by anyone and may result in unsolicited messages from other parties.

10.1 In this Section 10, we have summarized the rights that you may have under data protection laws depending on your location and country of residence. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

Here’s one of the most important parts about the new regulations and laws. You have the right to know all about what we collect, how we collect it, the right to move the data elsewhere and the right to have us delete your data and more. This is where you get to decide how your data is treated; you’re in control.

10.2 Your principal rights under data protection laws may include:

  * (a) the right to access;
  * (b) the right to rectification;
  * (c) the right to erasure;
  * (d) the right to restrict processing;
  * (e) the right to object to processing;
  * (f) the right to data portability;
  * (g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
  * (h) the right to withdraw consent.

10.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can access your personal data by visiting your profile when logged in.

Do we record and keep any of your data?

10.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

If we do, and it’s wrong, you can demand we correct it.

10.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay, and at the latest within one month of receiving your valid request. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully process. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

  * (a) We provide users with options to access and fully delete all of the data associated with their accounts, subject to any exclusions that may apply. Use the guide [below, or go to <https://support.visme.co/?s=delete> to use the self-serve deletion feature under your Account > Account Settings > Delete Your Account].
  * (b) How to Request Deletion of Your Account.  We recommend using this method only if you cannot delete your account yourself by logging in and using the instructions in section 9.5 a [above]. We can only delete data for people who can reasonably prove they are owners of the data in question. We will need to verify your ownership of the data. To submit this request, contact our support team by sending an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#bdcec8cdcdd2cfc9fdcbd4ced0d893ded2) and make sure to provide your Full Name, your Username associated with your account and your account#. 

You might have the right to erasure of your data; not always though so read the language carefully.

10.6 In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful, but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

10.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

10.8 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

You can always opt out of receiving marketing messages from us.

10.9 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

10.10 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

  * (a) consent; or
  * (b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

10.11 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

If you think we’ve done something wrong with your data and we haven’t resolved the issue, you can file a complaint with the government.

10.12 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

**11\. Children.**

The Company Service are not directed to people under the age of thirteen (13). If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at the email address listed below. If we become aware that a child under thirteen (13) has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child’s account.

11\. for K-12.  This clause does not apply when we are providing services to K-12.

**12\. Retaining and deleting personal data**

12.1 This Section 11 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

We will usually keep your data on record, until you tell us to delete it.

12.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall be kept until such time as we receive a request for deletion from you.

12.3 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 11, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

12\. Who can I ask if I have additional questions?

**12.4 for K-12.**  In addition to those rights as outlined in Section 12 above, we will delete a student’s Covered Information if the school or district requests deletion of data under the control of the school or district. 

For additional inquiries about the privacy of your information, you can contact us by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#32414742425d404672445b415f571c515d).
